JAY SONI

Address: D/503, Sahaj Prime, opp. Atithi Gokul hotel, Gota, Ahmedabad. India 382481 Tel: 9316425585 Email: Jaysony92@gmail.com

Profile Summary

Consultative, strategic and customer focused professional, Having Master of Business Administration and Master of Science (Biotechnology) accompanied with 4 years and 7 months of professional working experience in FMCG sales. Strong ability to build strategic business relations and remain on the cutting edge, driving new business through key accounts and establishing strategic partnerships to increase revenue. Target driven with the tenacity to maintain relations with high profit accounts. Well organised with self-motivation, creativity and initiative to achieve both personal and corporate goals. Positioned repeatedly as leading academic Person, sales specialist, star performer, Employee of the Quarter and other prestigious competitions, now looking to enhance career where I can deliver and excel more.

Education

MBA | GLASGOW CALEDONIAN UNIVERSITY (LONDON, UK CAMPUS)

JANUARY 2018 - MAY 2019

MSc BIOTECHNOLOGY | INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE, NIRMA UNIVERSITY: 74.3% JUNE 2013 - MAY 2015
A LEVELS: Biotechnology (A), Biochemistry (A), Molecular Biology (A) AND Microbiology (A)

BSc BIOTECHNOLOGY | M.N. SCIENCE COLLEGE, HEMCHANDRACHARYA NORTH **JUNE 2010 – APRIL 2013** GUJARAT UNIVERSITY, GUJARAT: **74.76**%

Key Strengths

- Sales & Key Account Management
- New Business Development
- Consultative & Solution Sales
- Pharmaceutical Sales
- Post-Sale Relationship Management

- Network & Relationship Building
- Budget Management
- Project Management & Deliverables
- Deliver Under Pressure & Deadlines

Career Overview

NUTRITION BUSINESS OFFICER NESTLE INDIA LTD., AHMEDABAD

November 2019 - Present

Executed direct sales model, establishing prospective medical relationships for Nestle products. Targeted focused territories, meeting medical product needs for Healthcare professionals, Pharmacists and Hospital departments. Interfaced with senior Doctors and Medical Stakeholders, negotiating high value contracts and coordinating implementation. Account managed and orchestrated post sale.

Key Accountabilities:

- Established alliances with key medical customers through cold calling business development, product presentations and technical meetings
- Built and maintained rapport with Senior Medical professionals, continually cross selling and identifying future sales opportunities
- Transformed underperforming sales, driving enhanced brand planning in partnership with Marketing team and creating marketing documents to enhance sales performance
- Spearheaded territory planning and management, continually monitoring competitor product & activities.
- Conceptualized and devised growth strategies, analyzing sales data and market share growth to identify performance variance and implement sales strategies
- Ensured continual development of company health services and products to enhance customer product offerings and promote new sales opportunities
- Interpreted and utilized Nestle clinical data, presenting within Health professional pitches to convey Competitive advantage
- Calculated customer contracts and handled promotional budget management

Shift Manager | SAKONIS RESTAURANT, LONDON

January 2018-June 2019

Deliver exceptional customer service to restaurant customers, providing informative menu choices and problem

Solution. Drive high standards across restaurant, delivering to sales and performance targets.

Key Accountabilities:

- Use active listening skills to understand customer requirements and provide informative menu options to suit individual, allergy and health focused needs
- Deliver to sales focused targets, continually updating knowledge on menu and service options to achieve KPI's and SLA's
- Focus on high standards of health & safety, identifying and remedying risks where required

EXPERT SALES EXECUTIVE | GLAXOSMITHKLINE CONSUMER HEALTHCARE, INDIA. June 2015-January 2018

Accomplished and energetic Nutrition Business officer with a solid history of achievements in the area of Medical Representation.

Key Accountabilities:

- Researching and identifying new business opportunities across markets, growth areas, partnerships, and any other ways of reaching new and existing clients
- Establishing and maintaining progressive customer relationships with key clients with the help of great communication and presentation skills
- Building and maintaining good business relationships with customers to encourage repeat purchase
- Able to identify current trends and build a successful pitch to drive sales for the relevant products and brands
- Keeping abreast of new developments in the medical field to determine the effect of such developments on company's business strategies.

Additional Information & Academic Achievements:

IT: Proficient in Microsoft Excel, word, outlook and PowerPoint

Academic Achievements:

Participated in Poster presentation in National Science Day | Nirma University 28th February 2015

Participated in IT-IMS Awareness Program | Indian Institute of Hardware Tech Ltd

C1 Band: SCOPE Examination | University of CAMBRIDGE (ESOL Examination) March 2012

Participated in "4th INSPIRE Internship Program/Science Conclave: November - December 2011

A Congratulation to Nobel Laureates and Eminent Scientists" | MHRD-DST Initiative at IIIT-A

A+ Grade | Environmental & Disaster Management Examination

Extra-Curricular Achievements:

Inter Institute Sports & Games Competitions | Nirma University: February 2015

First Prize: Javelin Throw Second Prize: Discus Throw

First Prize: Inter Institute Cricket Tournament: Nirma University 2014

Voluntary:

Worked within 120 People Team | Swami Vivekananda Charity Programme for Poor Children

Delivered within 10 People Team | Project for Blind People Association

References

References are available on request

